# Nomuunzul Munkhjargal

• (816) 394-6556 • nomuunzulm@gmail.com • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>GitHub</u> • <u>Portfolio</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

3+ years' experience in business and data analysis, 4+ years' experience in project management. Graduate student of M.A. in Economic specialized in environment. A pro-active and result-driven professional with long term goal to commit in ESG domain.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python (pandas, numpy, matplotlib), R, SQL Technologies: Excel, Power BI, Tableau, SAP, REDCap

Statistics: Regression modelling

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **American Century Investment Management, Inc**

Kansas City, Missouri

Data Analyst Intern, Business Transformation Dept.

May 2022 - Present

- Analysing customer behaviour from client service perspective and finding insights for the business to improve service quality, cost optimization and tailoring services to customer needs; presented findings to the stakeholders
- Transforming +3 manual reports into automatic self-service-oriented dashboard (Power-BI) achieving over 50man-hrs labour efficiency per annum

### University of Missouri – Kansas City

Kansas City, Missouri

Graduate Research Assistant, Center for Economic Information

Feb 2022 - Present

 Cleaned and transformed data that archived in various formats; contributed to the analysis on Impact Lead-Kansas City grant project

#### RioTinto LLC, Oyu Tolgoi Project

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Senior Business Analyst, Finance Dept.

June 2018 – January 2021

Business Analyst, Finance Dept.

October 2017 - May 2018

- Oversaw and provided analysis on value improvement investments of Concentrator plant to ensure informed management decision making
- Maintained and upgraded the life of mine cost models (Excel); conducted various analysis to support mine operations decisions of business improvement
- Originated and maintained monthly sustaining capital report (Power-BI)
- Supported on companywide ESG initiatives for value assessment and business case development, including Lean Procurement Practices for Reducing Wastes and Life cycle costing of Waste Management Center

## Project Lead, Engineering and Project Dept.

June 2016 - February 2017

Managed construction and engineering only projects, and successfully completed 16 projects in open pit, concentrator and, general and administration areas within approved acceptance criteria

#### Project Planner, Engineering and Project Dept.

August 2013 - May 2016

Monitored ongoing project progress and assessed it's earned value to ensure informed project management decision and scheduled contract payments

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Ecology

**University of Missouri-Kansas City** 

GPA: 3.86

Master of Arts in Economics

Expected December 2022

**National University of Mongolia** 

Earned 12 credits

**National United University in Taiwan** *Bachelor of Business Administration* 

GPA: 3.34

### **ORGANIZATIONS & INVOLVEMENTS**

Women in Mining Resources Mongolia

Founder & Former Board Member

December 2016 – December 2020

WMRM is a not-for-profit and non-governmental organization for society focused on promoting and guiding women in mining sector, their role and advancement in the industry